I see a lot of people figure it out to come early so good see you
我看到很多人很早就来了，很高兴见到你们
So as you recall,my name is Randy Bryant
如你们所知，我的名字是兰德尔·布莱恩特
And I'm co-instructor of this course along with Dave Hallaron
我是大卫·奥哈拉伦的合作导师
And for the next couple lectures the first part of this course really will be talking about a sort of data representations
接下来的几次课，我们主要讨论课程的第一部分数据的表示
In particular how numbers are represented in different forms and some of the properties and you saw that
特别是数字怎样以不同形式展示和它们一些对应的属性，你们会看到这些性质
When I talked last week I showed you things like
上周的课上，我给你们展示过类似的东西
You can multiply some numbers together that are positive and get negative result
你可以将一些正数相乘得到负数结果
So what we want to understand is what is the bit level representation of numbers
所以我们需要了解是数字的位级表示
And how does that affect some of the properties you have when you operate them on
当你操作它们时，会对其他属性有怎样的影响
and especially looking at the corner cases when things overflow
特别是在临界条件发生溢出时
We sort of don't do what, you might expect them to do
哪些我们不能做，哪些你期望它们实现
So we'll start off with very basic stuff of
所以我们从非常基本的东西开始
How numbers is represented especially integer valued numbers are represented in bits
如何表示数字，尤其是整数值的位级表示
Um so I think you pretty well figured out in this world that the whole digital world is sort of based on on binary values
恩，我觉得你们能很好的掌握基于二进制的数字世界
And that wasn't always the case I mean since humans have ten fingers and ten toes
但二进制并不总是适用，因为人类有十个手指和十个脚趾
A lot of the world was based on the decimal system
世界上的很多地方都是基于十进制的
And it was really only and in fact the first electronic computer the ENIAC built in University of Pennsylvania  basically encoded did all of its arithmetic using base ten
实际上只有宾夕法尼亚大学建立的第一台电子计算机 ENIAC 使用十进制进行了算术运算
They had ten vacuum tubes per digit they wanted to represent
他们使用 10 个电子管来表示每个数字
So they basically turned on or off those tubes to represent which of the ten possible digits you could want
所以他们通过控制电子管的开关来表示 10 个数字中的其中一个
And it really didn't come to people until later than that
十进制使用一些时间之后才使用二进制
So that's 1948 that they really should just think about base two for everything
1948年，他们应该考虑到了使用二进制构建一切
And the reason why bits are great is in the digital world you can sort of take what otherwise an analog signal and quantify it
比特之所以伟大的原因是在数字世界中你可以采取其他方式的模拟信号对其进行量化
And just say I'm going to say that one range of values
接下来我是用一组范围值来说明
Let's say it's a low voltage I'm going to call that a zero
假如低电压表示 0
And a high range of values I'm going to call it a one
我用某个高电压区间表示 1
And if there's noise or imperfections in the circuit or anything going on
如果电路中存在噪音或不完善之地方，或者其他干扰
As long as that doesn't exceed these bit these thresholds you've set up
只要不超过你设定的这些阈值
Then you'll get a nice clean signal out of it
你就会得到一个很清晰的信号
And that's the main advantage of digital processing over analog processing
这是数字处理和模拟处理相比的主要优势
And so that's sort of at the core why everything we do
这就是我们所做的一切的核心
And especially for storing information
特别是对于信息存储来说，它更容易存储
It turns out it's much easier to store one bit of information or a digital value than it is to store an analog value
事实证明，存储一位信息或一个数字值比存储一个模拟值要容易得多
And sorry this kind of slides went a little crazy on animations
（对不起，这个幻灯片的动画做的有点“疯狂”）
So the point is that we represent all the numbers in a computer as sets of bits
我们在计算机中使用比特位来表示所有数字
And I think you generally understand that fairly well
我认为你们大多都非常了解
And so of course the familiar binary representation of integers which we'll go over today
所以我们今天将要讨论使用熟悉的二进制表示整数
Just uses a bit position for each power of two we can also represent values that are fractional
使用比特位对应的 2 的幂我们可以表示分数
And we'll talk about that a week from today
我们将从今天开始讨论这个问题
When we do floating-point numbers where what you do is to the right of the binary point
当我们处理浮点数时，我们要怎么处理小数点右边的数字
So this is no longer a decimal point it's a binary point
所以这不再是一个十进制的小数点，它是一个二进制的小数点
And so something to the left of that would have a weight 2^0
小数点左边第一位的权重是 2^0
And the next one over would have weight 2^1
再向左一位的权重是 2^1
But what you do is as you go to the right that adds weight 2^-1,2^-2
但是当你处理小数点右边的数字时它们增加的权重是 2^-1, 2^-2
In other words this is 1,this is 2, this is 1/2 and this is 1/4
换句话说，这是 1，这是 2，这是 1/2，这是 1/4
So we can represent just like you do the decimal representation of fractions
所以我们可以使用这样的方式表示分数，就像分数的十进制表示一样
We can do the binary representation of fractions
我们可以使用二进制表示分数
And that's the core of floating-point number of representations
这是二进制表示浮点数的核心思想
And so it gets very annoying if you have say 32 or even 64-bit numbers to be writing the strings of 1 and 0 out
所以如果你见过数字写成 32 位甚至 64 位的 1 和 0 的字符串，那么它会变得非常烦人
And so what we use,and what's become largely the most common is to group collections of 4bits at a time into
所以我们通常将 4 比特的数据集合分组
And then represent that in base 16 or what's known as hexadecimal representation
然后用十六进制表示
Using the letters A through F as values 10 through 15
使用字母 A 到 F 作为值 10 到 15
And you'll spend a lot of time staring at hex decimal numbers this year
本学年你会花很多时间在不同的进制上，首先我们从十六进制数开始
And you'll get pretty good at being able to look at a hex number and just write it out in binary
而且当你看到一个十六进制数字你可以很快的写出它的二进制表示
The way I do it just to tell you is
我这样做只是为了告诉你们的是
I mean I've got the values from 0 to 9 wired down pretty well
我的意思是我已经获得从 0 到 9 的二进制表示
And then I keep track of a few special cases 1010 is A
然后我按照这个规律推导 1010 是 A
1100 is C and 1111 is F
1100 是 C，1111 是 F
And for B,D and E I kind of interpolate between those
而对于 B，D 和 E 在这些值之间
So if you want to develop that skill that's the way you can do it
所以如果你想发展这种技能，那就是你可以做到的
...and we learn HDMI connector that we can got here?...
... 我们能获得HDMI的神马知识么（学生提问）...
-No,I don't think there's any connector here. -no
-不，我不认为这里有任何联系 -没有
So that's something you're going to end up wanting to be able to do
所以这就是你希望最终能够做到的事情
So in C we don't...
所以在 C 语言中，我们不希望
In most declarations you don't actually are told exactly how many bytes
实际上在大多数声明中你并不能准确知道（变量有）多少字节
A byte is 8 bits
一个字节是由 8 个比特组成
Each data value is represented as
每种数据都是由字节组成
And that's partly C was designed actually back when microprocessors only had 16-bit words
这部分是 C 的设计时，当时微处理器实际上只有 16 位字
It was actually before microprocessors
它实际上是在微处理器之前
So 16-bit words were a fairly standard and over time that's expanded from 16 to 32 to now 64
所以 16 位字是一个相当标准的字，随着时间的推移，它从 16 位扩展到 32 位，现在是 64 位
And so C rather than a sort of an advanced thing
所以 C 而不是一种先进的东西
Here is how many bytes every value will have has these slightly ambiguous terms
这里是每个值有多少个字节会有这些含糊不清的术语
That vary actually from one machine to the next
从一台机器到另一台机器实际上有所不同
And if you're a very careful C programmer you have to anticipate that some
如果你是一个仔细的 C 程序员，你必须预料到一些情况
But what won't deal with is x86-64 is the class of machines will be working with exclusively this term
不过本学期我们只关注 X86-64 位机器，16 位，32 位我们不会涉及
And so you can see that when you declare something to be a care
所以你可以看到，当你声明一些关键词时需要特别小心
Sometimes people call it a char that's a 1 byte value
有时候人们称它为一个 char 类型的值是 1 个字节
A short is 16 bits
short 是 16 位
An int is 32 and if you want to get all 64 bits you have to declare it to be a long
一个 int 是 32 位，如果你想获得所有的都是 64 位，你必须声明它是一个 long
And then again there's two different representations of floating-point there's 4 byte or 32 bit of floating-point numbers and 64 bit
同样，浮点表示也有两种不同表示方法，4 个字节( 32 位)和 64 位两种浮点数
There's also a slightly obscure holdover from ancient days of floating-point
早期的浮点运算中也有一个稍微模糊的定义
Where there's a special representation in Intel machines that uses a 10 bytes or 80 bit representation
英特尔机器中使用 10 字节或 80 位的特殊表示
And when you use that on a 64-bit machine they sort of waste an extra 6 bytes out of that
当你在 64 位机器上使用它时，它们会浪费额外的 6 个字节
So that everything is aligned in 16 byte increments
这样一切都以 16 字节为增量对齐
The other thing and this is an important feature is any address is defined to be the sort of the word size of the machine
另一件事，这是一个重要的功能是虚拟地址空间是由机器字长决定的
When they say it's a 64-bit machine,what they really mean is that the addresses are 64-bit values or 8-byte values
当他们说这是一个 64 位机器时，他们的真正含义是这些地址是 64 位值或 8 字节值
And that's different for example if you use a older machine a 32-bit machine
如果你使用较旧的机器和 32 位机器，情况就不同了
Those will only be 32-bit addresses
那些只会是 32 位地址
So the basis sent I imagine you've had this at some point of how do we then think about bits is based on boolean algebra
在某些情况下，我们可以将比特想象成它来源于布尔代数
Which is actually comes from the 1890s that a guy named George Boole
（布尔代数）源于 1890 年代的一个名叫 George Boole 的人（准确的是 1850 前后）
Who recognized is sort of relation between what we'd call bits  but they weren't called bits back then
认为我们所谓的比特之间的关系，但当时他们并不称之为比特
0, 1 and logic are basically truth values in logic
0，1 是逻辑上最基础的值
I thinking of an algebra sort of a structured set of operations
我想到了一系列结构化操作的代数
You could apply that would capture some of the concepts that people assume in logic
你可以运用它来捕捉人们在逻辑中假设的一些概念
So for example if we think of 1 being true and 0 being false
例如，如果我们认为 1 是真的而 0 是假的
Then the and operation is true if both of the inputs the both of the arguments are true
然后，如果两个参数的两个输入均为真，则操作为真
so we get this chart here
所以我们在这里得到这张图表
Similarly the or operation is true if either input is true or 1
同样，如果任何一个输入为真或 1，则操作为真
The NOT is just to flip the bit
NOT 只是为了翻转这一点
And then the exclusive-or is what you get when you say it's one or the other but not both
然后异或是当你说它是相同为 0 相异为 1
And so it has this representation
所以它有这种表示结果
So just as a bit of history it was a master's degree student at MIT named Claude Shannon
回顾比特的历史，它是麻省理工学院的一位名为 Claude Shannon 的硕士生
Who had taken a course in logic as an undergraduate at University of Michigan
他曾在密歇根大学攻读逻辑学课程的本科生
And he was the one who made the connection between thinking about
而他是在思考之间建立联系的人
This this what was at the time very obscure branch of something a rather of logic
这在当时是非常模糊的东西，而非逻辑
And applying it to digital systems back in an era when they actually built
并将它应用到数字系统，回到他们实际构建的时代
These things out of electromechanical noise
这些东西没有机电噪音
And so his master's thesis is probably the most impactful master's thesis in the history of humankind
所以他的硕士论文可能是人类历史上最具影响力的硕士论文
And he always wonder well what did they do before that then
他总是很好奇他们在那之前做了什么
You know how do they even think about these things
你知道他们怎么看待这些事情
Anyways the idea of applying this algebra then to bits is not
无论如何，将这个代数应用于位的想法不是
Something that should have been true since the the world began
自从世界开始以来本应该是真的
Something that's a relatively modern concept
这是一个相对现代的概念
Now what's an important thing that might be less obvious is we can also do these over words
现在可能不那么明显的一件重要事情是，我们也可以用言语来做这些事情
We can do these boolean operations where we apply them on each successive bit in that word
当我们操作连续的比特时，可以认为是对每个比特位使用布尔操做
And these symbols we use the &, | and ~
我们使用 ＆ | ~ 这些符号来操作
are actually the ones that see use is to represent these operations
实际上是用来代表这些操作
And so again if we look at here the 1 is only if both of the values 1
如果我们再看这里，那么 1 就是两个值都是 1
And the for the OR for the AND for the one
相比与 AND，对于 OR 来说产生 1 的方式是
OR its if either of them are 1
它们中的任何一个是 1
The exclusive or if 1 is 1 and the other is zero
如果是异或，1^1 是 0
And tilde is just to invert the bits of it
~（非）只是反转它的位
So again we will spend a lot of time making use of the fact that in C
所以我们将花费大量的时间在 C 语言中使用并实现这些逻辑
And this is one of the features to C that people like
这是人们喜欢的 C 特性之一
is that you can do these sort of very low level of bit manipulations directly in the language
你可以直接在语言中执行这些低级别的位操作
and um
嗯
This actually turns out to be useful in practice
这实际上在实践中证明是有用的
And it's sort of implicit of a way of representing sets of values
这是隐含着一种表示值集合的方式
So this example is a imagine we want to represent sets
所以这个例子是想象我们要表示集合
Where the elements of the set are numbers ranging between 0 and 7
该集合由 0 到 7 之间的整数组成
So 1 byte is enough to capture eight cases
所以 1 个字节足以表示 8 种情况
And we'll just if we number the bits and we number them from right to left
我们只需要对这些位进行从右向左编号即可
So this is bit 0 so that would represent whether or not the value 0 is an element of the set
所以第 0 位表示 0 是否是该集合的一个元素
And similarly here you'll see 0,1,2,3
同样在这里你会看到 0,1,2,3
So we're seeing that bit 3 being one here means 3 is an element of the set and so forth
我们看到第 3 位是 1，这意味着 3 是这个集合中的一个元素，等等
and the
和
So the idea is then the AND operation becomes like set intersection
所以 AND（&） 操作变得像集合交集
The OR operation becomes like set Union
OR（|）操作变得像集合的并
And the X-OR operation is what's called symmetric difference
而异或（X-OR）操作就是所谓的对称差异
And so these are actually and ~ is like set complement
所以实际上 〜 即为集合的补集
So these are actually very common for example
这些实际上很常见
There are operations you'll learn later when we look at a file I/O
稍后我们会在查看文件 I/O 时学到一些操作
About I/O that you can track I want to know which set of possible inputs to the system
关于 I/O 你可以跟踪你想知道系统可能有哪些输入
think of different network connections have an input ready for me to read
想想不同的网络连接有一个输入可供我阅读
And there is a data structure that
并且有一个数据结构
It's sort of hidden away among some C library calls
它可能隐藏在多个 C 语言库调用中
But it basically is using exactly this representation about a thousand
但它基本上使用了大约一千个这种表示
A bits worth of information to represent these sets
有价值的信息来表示这些集合
And do manipulation on those sets so this is a very common
并且对这些设置进行操作，所以这是非常常见的
And why do we use representation of sets in computer science
这就是为什么我们在计算机科学中使用集合表示
so as I mentioned those are available directly in C the &,|, ~ and ^
所以我刚才提到那些可以直接在 C 语言中使用是＆，|，～和^
One thing that's really really important and that programmers screw it up all the time
有一件事情真的非常重要，程序员总是把它搞砸
Beginning programmers a lot and even experienced programmers from time to time is to mix up the & in the &&
很多初级程序员，有时甚至是经验丰富的程序员都会混淆 ＆ 在 &&
or the | and the ||
或 | 和 ||
and the ~ versus the exclamation mark which is often pronounced bang
而 〜 与 ! 经常读作 "bang"
so and the reason
造成混淆原因是
So obviously there's sort of a syntactic similarity
所以显然有句法相似之处
And there's actually a somewhat of a semantic relation to that
而且实际上有一些与此有关的语义关系
This is another kind of AND another kind of OR and another kind of NOT
这是另一种 AND 的另一种 OR 和另一种 NOT
But if you mix and match these you're certainly going to have problems
但是，如果使用时混淆这些，你肯定会遇到问题
So the || ones aren't thinking about bitwise operations through thinking about something that's either true or false period
所以人们不会认为 || 是位操作，而是会考虑一段时间内条件的真假
And in that representation the number 0 is the thing that's false
在这个表示中，数字 0 是假
And anything else any other bit pattern is considered to be true
而其他任何其比特表示的数字都被认为是真
The other feature that the || give you is what's called early termination
|| 的另一个特点让你的调用提前终止
So in particular if we do some examples
现在我们举一些特定的例子
On the some hex pattern for 1, so this is a not a 0  and so that's considered true
产生 0x01 是因为非零数会被认为是真
So the the bang of that the not of that is 0
而对这个值取“非”就是 0
The same way if you have 0 the not event is 1
同样如果是 0，那么 “非”0 就是 1
And if you apply bang to a number twice you'll get back a 1 unless it was 0
如果你对一个非零数应用两次 !，你会得到 1
And then the same these patterns here
这里也是类似的情况
The reason why this returns 1 is because it's considered two cases that are true
这里返回 1 的原因是这里的两个条件都是真
So it's not doing bitwise operations it's just trying to create true and false
所以这不是位操作，而是判断“真”“假”
It's interpreting arguments be there true or false and returning either true or false
它根据的参数的 “真”“假”，返回 “真” 或 “假”
But when it returns true it returns one and not whatever number you happen to give
但是当它返回“真”时返回的是 1，而不是你碰巧给出的任何数字
So obviously this is a very different operations than you have with the single versions of those and
显然这和位操作完全不同
But it's easy just because you mentally slip or because you type something wrong to do the wrong thing
但是这种情况在你你一时疏忽，或者误操作时很容易出现
But in particularly this early termination is something that of course people use a lot
特别是“提前终止”这种特性被很多人用到的时候
If you want to make sure that you're not accessing a null pointer
如果你想确保你没有访问空指针
You can test whether that's a null pointer first before accessing it
你可以在访问它之前先测试它是否为空指针
And this if this is 0 or null then it will do the the dereferencing of null
如果这是 0 或 null，就能避免对 null 的引用
So it's a fairly useful feature as well
所以这也是一个相当有用的功能
So anyways just that's an aside at this level we're mostly looking at bits
所以无论如何，在这个层面上，我们大多数都是看比特
But just as a programming no don't mix these up
但就像编程一样，不要混淆
The other class of operations will make use of a lot our shifting
其他位操作中我们使用次数最多的就是位移
Which again is not something that you normally sort of as beginning programmers think about too much
这不像很多初级程序员所思考的那样
And if there's a curious feature that a left shifts are always the same
位移有一个奇怪的功能就是左移总是相同的
But there's two different flavors of right shift
但是它有两种不同的右移方式
And we'll see in a little bit later why there's two different flavors of right shift
稍后我们会看到为什么有两种不同的右移方式
But um
但是
The idea that of shifting is that you have some argument x
移位的思想是你有一个参数 x
And you want to shift it some number of positions either to the left or to the right given by y
你想要将它的位置向左或向右移动一些位置
And so when you shift left you just fill in whatever value there was so you pick up the
当你向左移动时，你不需要管填充什么数字，只需要管位移
I'm shifting by three,so I'll take the low order five bits move them over three positions
当我左移 3 位时，我会把低位的 5 个比特向左移动 3 位
Then fill in with a zero
然后在低位填零
And whatever was in the upper positions of that original words they just sort of disappear into nowhere
而原始数据中的高位都会消失无踪
Similarly if I do a right shift I take the upper six bits I move them over to positions and I fill in with zeros
同样，如果我做右移，我将把高位移动相应的位置，然后用零填充
So that's a logical shift and that's well it's logic
所以这是一个逻辑右移，这就是逻辑
There's another flavor called the arithmetic shift
还有另外一种叫算术转换
Which it differs in that the rule for what bits you fill in with are not based on the are
它的不同之处在于填充的规则不是固定的
not zeros necessarily but it's whatever the most significant bit was in the original value
不一定是零，但它是原始值中的符号位
So it doesn't matter here because the most significant bit was zero
所以这里没关系，因为符号位是零
But you'll see in the case here of where the leading bit was a 1
但在这里你看到首位是 1
That when I shift it to the right arithmetic we I'll fill it in with 1
当我进行右移时，我将用1填充它
And that'll make sense more when we understand how negative numbers get represented in a machine
当我们理解负数在机器中的表示形式就能明白其中的含义
And that's the purpose of it and why it's called arithmetic
以及这样设计的目的，和为什么它被称为算术右移
Um the other thing is confusing to people is
另一件事让人感到困惑
What should happen if you say I want to shift an 8-bit number 8 positions to the left
如果你说我想将一个 8 位数的 8 位移到左边，应该发生什么
And X is a single byte what do you think you should get
而 x 是一个单字节，你认为你应该得到什么?
Zero that would be a pretty logical thing you kind of shift all those bits out you fill them with zeros
零这将是一个非常合乎逻辑的事情，你把所有这些位移出来，你用零填充它们
On most machines you'll get whatever x was
在大多数机器上你会得到 0
Because what will do is it will compute this number mod 8
因为它将要做计算是将这个数字模 8
And the reason that happens is if you think about it
你们考虑一下发生这种情况的原因
It's looking at just the lower two three bits of the shift amount and ignoring all the rest
只要观察低位的 3 个比特位移，忽略所有其他位
So that's effectively like module 8
所以这就像模 8 一样
So that's just a warning and some machines it does
一些机器只是会给出警告提示
What you just thought it should and other machines it does this
你只是认为它应该和其他机器这样做
And so there's no no guarantee and in C that it will be one way or the other
因此在 C 语言当中不能保证只有一种方式
Same with if you try to shift left by a negative number that might be logically
同样如果你尝试向左移动可能是逻辑上的负数
Well I guess you really want to shift right then but that usually doesn't work either
那么我想你真的想要正确地转移，但通常也不起作用
So now let's talk about number representations
现在让我们来谈谈数字表示
And
和
This is sort of a very core its idea that you have to really have wired in you
这是它的一个非常核心的想法，你必须用心理解他
And I'm going to illustrate it with some examples
我将用一些例子来说明它
So the these two equations that are everything that we'll talk about sort of stems from them
所以这两个方程就是我们要谈论的一切，都源于他们
So one is if you have an unsigned number
所以一个是如果你有一个无符号的数字
Then basically...it keeps jumping on me
然后基本上...（它不断打扰我）
If you have an unsigned number then this is just the conversion
如果你有一个无符号的数字，那么这只是转换
B2U means from a bit level representation to an unsigned number of some bit pattern
B2U的意思是从比特位模式的无符号数的编码表示
It just says we'll just add up the sum of the weighted bits
它意思是我们将加权位求和（看屏幕左上角那个公式）
Where each bit is weighted by a power of two
每个比特用2的幂来加权
And the only difference when we look at two's complement
唯一的区别就是我们看两个补码
Which is a way to represent both negative and positive numbers
这种方法可以表示负数和正数
It's we'll consider the most significant bit to be what's called the sign bit
这里我们认为最重要的一点是所谓的符号位
So it will have a negative value
所以它会有一个负值
So let me just illustrate this with I'll use some running examples
所以让我来说明一下，我将使用一些运行示例
We'll just use five bit numbers just as a way it really helps often if you're trying to understand  this stuff to do it for some smaller cases
我们只会使用五位数字，使用较小的位数通常可以帮助你们理解补码
So if we think about bit positions
所以如果我们考虑比特的位置
zero through four
从零到四
Then those represent of different powers of two weights of as I've shown
我写的这些数字表示 2 的不同幂的值
And so now if we take some bit a pattern
如果我们采取位模式
Like so
像这样
So that's what I'll call X
我把它叫做 X
and if I want to convert that to an unsigned number
如果我要将其转换为无符号数
I will just combine 8+4+1 and I'll get 13
我只需要 8+4+1，我会得到 13
all right
好吧
So that's all that equation says the left hand equations just take the the bit positions that are ones use the corresponding power of 2 and you're done
所以这个方程式展示的等式左边只是将对应比特位的 2 的幂累加，就能得到结果
And similarly if I have a number where there's a leading bit
同样的，如果我有一个数字，最高位是 1
It will be 16+4+2  so that will be 22
它将是 16+4+2，因此将是22
And so that's the unsigned case
这是无符号的情况
And the sign case is the same idea
有符号数情况是一样的想法
Except that most significant bit has a negative value
除了最高位是负值
So it will still this is i
所以它仍然是 i
And our weights will be 1,2,4,8
我们的权重将是 1,2,4,8
But this will be -16
但是这将是 -16
So that's what the equation on the right is saying this fit
所以这就是右边的这个公式所说的
Now we're going to change it from being a negative number to a positive
现在我们要把它从一个负数变成一个正数
So obviously if I have this is my bit pattern it's going to be the same because
所以很显然，如果我有这是我的位模式，它将是相同的，因为
The other bits stayed at the same so let's do it for this case of 10110
其他位保持不变，所以让我们来做这个 10110 的情况
So that will be -16+4+2=-10
所以这将是 -16+4+2=-10
So you see in this case we have the same bit pattern
所以你在这种情况下看到我们有相同的位模式
It's just if we interpret it you know how we think about what number this represents
只是如果我们解释它，你就知道我们如何看待这个代表的数字
Then in one case it's a positive number 22 in another case it's a negative number -10
那么在另一种情况下，这是一个正数 22，在另一种情况下，它是一个负数 -10
And that's what these equations you see
这就是你看到的这些方程
And so the most significant bit is sometimes called the sign bit because
因此，最高位有时称为符号位
If it's a 1 the number is going to be negative
如果它是 1，则该数字将是负数
So let's sort of think about
所以让我们思考一下
What extreme,what are the sort of extreme ranges of numbers
极值是多少，可以表示的数在那个区间
We can get with these two different representations
在这两种不同数的表示方式下我们得到不同的区间
So obviously if these are all zeros my number is going to equal zero
所以显然，如果这些都是零，我能得到 0
And if it's all 1 it will be 16+8+4+2+1 will be 31
如果全是 1，那么将是 16+8+4+2+1 将是31
And over here for the two's complement
在这里展示一下补码的情况
The smallest number,well the largest number will actually be let me do it this way
最小的数字，最大的数字会是，让我这样做
Actually the most negative number so the smallest number and the strictest sense of the word is
其实严格的讲最小的负数是最小的数字
is this it's -16. you can argue this by the way
这是 -16，你可以使用这种方式来论证
This is the only bit that has a negative weight all the other ones have positive ones
这是唯一一个负数权重的比特位，所有其他都是正数
So certainly one and all the rest being zeros is going to be the smallest number
所以第一位是 1 其余所有位都是 0 就是最小的数字
And similarly the largest number you can represent
同样，你可以得到最大的数
We'll be 8+4+2+1 which is 15
8+4+2+1 这是 15
And so we call this number UMax
我们把这个数字称为 UMax
And we call this number TMax
我们称这个数为 TMax
And we call this number TMin
我们把这个数叫做 TMin
So there's a few things to observe about these numbers
这几个数有几点需要注意的
That remember this is a 5-bit word size right so
请记住，这是字长位 5 的情况
You'll see that 31 is pretty close to 32 right
你看到 31 很接近 32
In fact it's 2^5-1
实际上它是 2^5-1
And in general if it's a five and that's for a 5-bit word size
一般来说，如果字长是 5
So you would say in general it will have value 2^w if I have a W bit number minus 1 and that's what this shows
一般来讲如果你有 w 位数，你能的到的值就是 2^(w-1)，就像这个呈现的一样
And similarly over here this is -2^4
同样，这是 -2^4
And so we'd say in general that will be -2^w if it's a W bit number minus 1
一般来说我们有 w 位数，一般会说，我们能到的值是 -2^(w-1)
Right all these make sense by the way you'll notice one other feature is
所有这些都是有道理的，你会注意到另一个特征是
A whole string of ones like this if you sum up those digits 8 + 4 + 2 + 1
像这样一整串数字都是由 1 组成，如果你把它们每位表示的值相加
Will be 1 less than the next bit position up
得到的值将比前一位表示的值少 1
And you can think about that if you were to count this number
你可以考虑计算一下这个数字
If you were to increment this number by 1 you'd get 1 1 is 0 carry 1 and so forth
如果你将这个数字加 1，你会看到 1 加 1 得 0 进 1，一次类推
And you'd carry that value up to this position so these various ways you can think about that
你得到的值就是这个位置表示的数，所以你可以用这些不同的方式来思考
And then similarly this number is 2^4-1
同样这个数字是 2^4-1
And so that's equal to 2^(w-1) - 1
等于 2^(w-1)-1
As is shown here
如这里所示
So there's a lot of the book goes through formulas and does derivation
有很课本都是通过公式来推导
But if you just think about it in these smaller scale ways
但是，如果你只是用很小规模的来思考它
The intuition is pretty easy to get and don't get lost in in formulas when
就能很直观的感受到这种规律，并且在公式中不会迷失方向
Really at the gut level it's a fairly straightforward sort of ideas
真正在内心深处，这是一个相当直接的想法
Or if you ever see some confusions and you're confused
或者如果你看到一些混乱，你感到困惑
Try out some small examples and see what they're saying
尝试一些小例子，看看他们在说什么
Another interesting number in the world of two's complement  is what happens when you have all ones in your bit patterns
二进制补码世界中还有另一个有趣的数字，当所有的位都是 1 时候会发生什么
And that will have mate -16+8+4+2+1 and that will equal -1
这将得到 -16+8+4+2+1，等于 -1
So the bit pattern all ones is always a -1 in this representation
所以在这种表示中，所有的位都是 -1
I should mention two's complement is not the only way to represent a positive and negative numbers
我应该提到过补码并不是表示正数和负数的唯一方式
what's sometimes called signed numbers
有时称为有符号数字
But it's so universal that you'll hardly ever encounter another case
但它很普遍，你几乎不会遇到另一种情况
So if you understand two's complement you have a pretty good understanding of  what really is going on
所以，如果你理解了补码，你就能很好地理解真正发生了什么
So these numbers I call UMax the biggest unsigned number
这些数字中 UMax 最大的无符号数字
TMin the smallest most negative two's complement monitor and
TMin 是补码的最小值
TMax the largest most positive two's complement
TMax 是补码的最大值
This chart shows the range of values for different word sizes different numbers of bytes
此图表显示了不同字长数值的范围
And so you'll see that with an 8 bit number you only have 256 possibilities right
所以你会看到， 8 位只有 256 个可能
And so we can either choose to rate think of those as representing the range from 0 to 255
因此，我们可以选择将其视为表示的范围是从 0 到 255
Or basically with two's complement numbers we're just doing a sort of a wraparound we're saying
或者基本上用二进制补码来表示，我们只是在做一个简单的说明
Well we're going to have half of them be negative and the other half will be either 0 or positive
那么我们将有一半是负数，另一半是 0 或正数
And so it's a pretty limited range of values of course
所以这当然是一个相当有限的值范围
Then 16 and believe me back when computers had 16-bit word sizes
然后 16，当计算机有 16 位字长时，请相信我
It was a nuisance to keep your numbers within that range
将数字保持在该范围内是一件令人讨厌的事情
And 32 gives you a pretty decent range it used to be said
而 32 给你一个相当不错的范围，曾经有人说过
Microsoft had to go to 64-bit word size to represent Bill Gates's net worth but
微软必须以 64 位字大小来表示比尔盖茨的净资产，但是
For me at least this would easily handle my range of normal day-to-day transactions so
至少对我来说，这很容易处理我正常的日常交易范围
But now with 64 bits at least to us nowadays those seem like really big numbers and  hard to imagine exceeding the bounds of those
但现在至少对我们来说，64 位数字看起来非常庞大，很难想象它们超出了这些限制
So one interesting feature that you noticed here was I was um
所以你注意到的一个有趣的功能就是
like this case here
像这里的情况一样
In this case here...
在这里这里...
And then this case here  of all ones
然后在这里所有的情况
I was comparing it to this case here of all ones
我在这里比较所有的这种情况
So in other words in both these cases and it's a little hard to jump boards here
换句话说，在这两种情况下，（这个黑板不好抬...）
You're seeing that you have the same bit pattern in either case
无论哪种情况，你都会看到相同的位模式
But they the numeric they represent different numeric values because one is a two's complement case
但他们的数字代表不同的数值，因为一个是补码
And the other is an unsigned right
另一个是无符号数
And you can actually see the relation between them is pretty simple
你可以看到它们之间的关系非常简单
Because basically what we're doing is we're jumping between +16 and -16 between those
因为基本上我们正在做的是我们在这些之间的 +16 和 -16 之间变化
And so you'd expect it to change by 32 right
所以你会期望它改变为 32
And you see that here that this is 31 here and -1
你在这里看到，这里是 31 和 -1
This is 22 and -10 so they're differ from each other by plus  -32 ,2^4, two to the word size
这是 22 和 -10，所以他们是不同的，加上 -32，2^4，
and so we there's sort of a long derivation in the book and things here
所以我们在这本书和这里的东西中有很长一段时间的推导
But that connection is actually fairly important
但是这种联系实际上相当重要
Because when you jump back and forth between unsigned numbers and two's complement numbers in C
因为当你在 C 中的无符号数和补码之间跳来跳去
That's the jump that you get in other words
换句话说，这就是跳跃
when of and so
何时等等
You'll often find cases where what used to be a very large number
你经常会发现过去曾经是一个非常大的数字的情况
Because it was unsigned all of a sudden becomes a negative number
因为它是无符号数，突然变成了一个负数
Because it's considered two's complement
因为它被认为是补码
So that's what this next part covers will say that
所以接下来的部分就是这么说的
If we take a cart of 4 bit numbers and
如果我们使用一个 4 位的数值模式
We write out all the possible values is unsigned or as  two's complement numbers
我们写出所有可能的值都是无符号或二进制补码
Then the ones where the low the higher bit is 0 will be the same in both cases
那么在最高位是 0 的情况下，两种表示方式的值是相同的
The ones where the higher order bit is a 1 in this case will differ by 16 2^4
在这种情况下，最高位是 1，它们将相差 16, 2^4
And similarly you'll notice that these numbers there's a unique
同样你会注意到这些数字是唯一的
It goes unique in both directions there's a for any given bit pattern
它在两个方向都是独一无二的，适用于任何给定的位模式
There's a unique number it represents and
有一个独特的数字代表和
And similarly for any number within the given range there's a unique bit pattern
同样，对于给定范围内的任何数字，都有一个唯一的位模式
So we can sort of jump between those two and say
所以我们可以在这两者之间跳跃并说
I can make up a rule for converting between a two's complement number X  and an unsigned number UX
我可以定义一个在补码 X 和一个无符号数字 UX 之间转换的规则
That basically says I'll use the same bits I'll just think of them as being different numbers
基本上说，我会使用相同的位，我只是认为它们是不同的数字
And so and you can go either way
所以你可以去任何一个方式
So for example if we thought of this is a a two's complement representative representation,  it's -1
举例来说，如果我们认为这是补码表示，这是数是 -1
This function I'm calling T2U goes from that number -1 to this number 31
我调用 T2U 的这个函数，就能将 -1 这个数转成 31
Where in between the two I'm saying they both have the same bit pattern
在两者之间我说他们都有相同的位模式
And the reason why this rather function that would otherwise seem to have no particular use is important
而这个功能似乎没有特别用处的原因很重要
Because that's basically what happens in C or actually in the program
因为这基本上是 C 或实际在程序中发生的事情
On the computer itself has no clue whether a given bit pattern if it's something
在计算机上本身并不知道是否给定位模式
You're thinking of as being a negative number or two's complement number it's just a bunch of bits to it
你正在考虑作为一个负数或二进制补码，它只是一堆比特
And similarly so we can go back and forth between a two's complement and unsigned  keeping the bit patterns the same
同样，我们可以在补码和无符号二进制之间来回保持位模式相同
And so I'll call that T2U when I go from signed to unsigned two's complement unsigned
所以当我从 signed 到 unsigned 二进制补码无符号时，我会调用该 T2U
And say well I'll call U2T if I go from unsigned to signed
如果我从 unsigned 到 signed 我会调用 U2T
And as I mentioned the difference for the the numbers where the high-order bit is a 1
正如我提到的最高位是 1 的数字的区别
will be by a factor 2^w where w is the word size of the word
乘以一个因子 2^w，其中 w 是所在位的权值
And so this can be thought of as a function
所以这可以被认为是一种功能
Where
哪里
Let me just draw it up
让我把它画出来
Over here with my five of bit numbers
在这里用我的五位数字
That is the number this is two's complement again so that was the number -16
这是这个数字，这又是 2 的补码，所以这是数字 -16
And then there'll be some other negative numbers up to all ones
然后会有一些其他的负数直到所有的负数
This is number negative one
这是数字是负数
Then I'll have zero and so forth and then all up to
然后我会有零等等，然后一切
+15
Destroys,I got myself in trouble
我陷入了麻烦
Blackboard management is they didn't teach me this in school
黑板管理们没有在学校教我这个
So I'm gonna use two boards and ones here
所以我要在这里使用两块黑板
Okay let me send this out,okay we'll make it work
好，让我推上去，好了我们继续
So now when we go from the T2U function then
所以现在我们从 T2U 函数开始
These numbers are going to just carry over
这些数字将继续存在
We'll get 0 up through 15
我们会从 0 到 15
But now this number here will become positive 16
但现在这个数字会变成正数 16
And all ones will become positive 31 right
所有的位都是 1 会得到 +31
And so that's what this picture is showing is it for the pink numbers
所以这张照片显示的是粉色数字
are the ones that flip between negative and actually the largest of the positive numbers
是那些在负数和实际上最大的正数之间翻转的数字
And then the green numbers are the ones that stay the same because they're leading bits or zeros
然后绿色数字保持不变，因为它们的最高位是 0
So why does this matter bits or zeros
那么为什么这有点重要
You never thought if you programmed in Python  or even Java
如果你用 Python 或甚至 Java 编程，你就不会考虑这些
You don't see that and the reason is because C is one of the few languages where unsigned is actually an explicit datatype
你没有看到这一点，原因是因为 C 是少数 unsigned 是一个明确的数据类型的语言之一
So you can declare a value being unsigned
所以你可以声明一个 unsigned 的值
And it's you can if you just say unsigned what you're really saying is unsigned int
如果你只是说 unsigned 你真正的意思是 unsigned int
Or you can call something an unsigned care and unsigned short or an unsigned long
或者你可以调用一些 unsigned short 或 unsigned long
So and you're declaring and see that it should think about using this representation we show on the right
所以你在使用时应该考虑使用我们在右边展示的这个表示
When it's working on those numbers
当它在处理这些数字时
So that's sort of one thing and this it's one thing if you declare a number and use it that way
如果你声明了一个数字并以这种方式使用它
But what gets people and the often got you is if you declare something if you have a in this case
但是，如果你在这种情况下拥有某种东西，那么获得人们和经常得到你的是什么
Something that's declared as a two's complement number X to TX
一些声明为 TX 的补码数X的事物
And you assign it a value you at Y X it'll do an implicit casting
你在 Y X 给它赋值，它会进行隐式转换
Which is exactly based on this conversion that we've been talking about and vice versa
这正是基于我们一直在谈论的这种转换，反之亦然
And so as this example goes through this goes through some examples that
所以这个例子告诉我们
If I look at two numbers and I compare them or I actually I do any operation on them
如果我看看两个数字，然后比较它们，或者实际上我会对它们进行一些操作
I add them divide them anything implicitly it will try to make these to be of the same type
我将它们求和、或分开，从而尝试使它们成为相同的类型
And the way it will do that is to say if both of them are signed
而这样做的方式就是说如果两个数都是有符号数
Then I'll do I'll treat them as a signed case
那么我会做我会把他们作为一个 signed 的情况
If either of them is unsigned
如果其中任何一个无符号
Then I'll convert the other one to be an unsigned number and do the operation
然后我会将另一个转换为一个无符号数并进行操作
And so in particular this set of examples is imagine
特别是通过这个例子可想而知
I'm comparing these I'm saying these numbers are either equal less or greater
我比较这些我说这些数字要么等于或大于等于
What will the outcomes be and the key to answering that question is to first of all figure out
结果会是什么，回答这个问题的关键首先要弄清楚
Okay is it a signed or an unsigned comparison should I convert
好的，这是否是一个有符号或无符号的比较，我是否需要转换
One of these numbers to either of these numbers to an unsigned form before I do it
这些数字之一，这些数字之前，我这样做了一个无符号的形式
And the rule was if either argument is unsigned then you got to do it
而规则是如果任何一个无符号数，那么你必须这样做
And as you see when you put a u at the end either a  u or U at the end of a numeric constant
正如你所看到的，当你在结尾处放置一个 u 或 U 时，它就是一个数字常量的末尾
You're saying this is an unsigned value
这是一个无符号值
So for example if we compare a zero and zero unsigned they're equal
举例来说，如果我们比较零和无符号零，它们是相等的
And if we combine negative one compare negative one to zero
如果我们比较 -1 和 0
We'll get that the first one is less
我们会得到第一个小于
Because -1 is less than 0
因为 -1 小于 0
But what would happen with the next one when we compare negative 1 to an unsigned 0
但是当我们将 -1 与无符号 0 进行比较时，会发生什么
greater right
更大，对吧
So this is the surprise and it has to do with...a number that I erased
所以这是一个惊喜，它与我擦掉的一个数字有关
But we can still get it remember this is negative one
但我们仍然可以记住这是 -1
But when I cast that to an unsigned number
但是当我把它转换成一个无符号数时
I'm flipping this from -16 to +16 and turning this into 31 I'm turning it into actually the largest number I can represent
我把这个从 -16 改为 +16，并把它变成 31，我把它变成了我能代表的最大数字
And so it will be greater than zero
所以它会大于零
So it's a little bit weird to think about I took an u0 which after all is to 0  and compared it to a negative 1
所以有点奇怪的是，我想到了一个 u0，它毕竟是 0，并将其与 -1 进行比较
And it said oh you really meant 31 didn't you or whatever word size we're using
它说哦，你真的意味着 31 或我们正在使用的任何字号
And so it said it's greater
所以它说这更大
And basically the rest of these you can answer in a similar way
基本上其余的你可以用类似的方式回答
That these two numbers are this is clearly one smaller than this
这两个数字是这个数字显然小于这个数字
No I'm sorry this is a positive this is a negative number and
不，我很抱歉，这是正的，这是一个负数
I compare those and the positive will be greater than the negative
我比较这些正数的将大于负数
I'll tell you in a minute why this number is written this way
我会在一分钟内告诉你为什么这个数字是这样写的
The next one it's the same pair of numbers
下一个它是同一对数字
But you see it's flipped
但你看它翻转了
And the reason is this number on the left is TMax for
原因是这个左边的数字是 TMax 的
So it's the bit pattern in a 32-bit number
所以这是 32 位数字中的位模式
And to this day I have not memorized this number by the way
直到今天，我还没有记住这个数字
But and then this number is actually TMin
但是，这个数字实际上是 TMin
And that when I subtract you can think of it as this is negative TMax - 1 so that's TMin
而当我减去时，你可以认为它是负的 TMax-1，所以这就是 TMin
So if I do an unsigned comparison between those two now think of those
所以，如果我现在想一下这两者之间的无符号比较
This leading bit  not being a negative weight But a positive weight you'll see that this is a bigger number than this one
这个领先位不是一个负面的权重，但一个正面的权重，你会看到这是一个比这个更大的数字
And so it goes that -1 is greater than -2 if they're unsigned
因此，如果它们是无符号的，则 -1 大于 -2
Because -1 is you can think of it as converts into UMax it'll be the biggest number possible
因为 -1 可以把它看作转换成 UMax，它可能是最大的数字
And -2 will be would be 11110
-2 将会是 11110
So that can get fairly confusing
所以这可能会让人相当困惑
One final quirk this way of writing this number is there's a little side in the book about it
写这个数字的最后一个怪癖是书中有一点关于它的一面
If you write a business number Oh as you'd expect - as - blah blah blah 648
如果你写一个商业编号哦，正如你所期望的那样 - 吧啦吧啦 648
It will actually get the C compiler gets kind of confused by that for obscure reasons
它实际上会让 C 编译器因为一些模糊的原因而感到困惑
One other thing I should point out that it's a property that I don't think we cover well enough here
还有一件事我应该指出，这是一个性质，我认为我们在这里覆盖得不够好
Let me see
让我看看
There's a few things that the tides don't really cover here and I don't know why not
这里有一些趋势并不真正涵盖在这里，我不知道为什么不
They like to point out
他们喜欢指出
That are kind of useful properties to keep track of
这是一些有用的特性可以跟踪
It's that you notice that if you look at the absolute value of TMax
这是你注意到，如果你看看 TMax 的绝对值
And you compare it to the absolute value of TMin
你将它与 TMin 的绝对值进行比较
That it's off by one right
它们相差 1，对吧
So that the negative number is more negative
所以负数更小
The smallest negative number is more negative than the largest positive number is positive
最小的负数比最大的正数更负
And the reason for that actually is fairly simple if you think about
如果你想一想，其中的原因其实很简单
It is that the cases where you have zeros
这是你有零的情况
Include the number 0
包含数字 0
So you can see it better
（这样你们能看的更清楚）
And there's two to the half-year range is occupied by those numbers
近半年我们会讲这些数字
And the negative numbers are all negative
负数都是负数
And there's so the other half of the range is in there
另外还有一半是在那里
And the point is that you had to use one of these four zero
关键是你必须使用这四个零中的一个
And so they're only there's one left one less value left over
所以他们只剩下一个剩下的价值
And that's why you end up with this through asymmetry
这就是造成不对称性的原因
And this asymmetry is the cause of no end of pain in various ways
而这种不对称性通过各种方式造成了无尽的困扰
That like a few the classic example is if you implement absolute value
这就像一些经典的例子，如果你实现绝对值
Like so what do you what does this return for TMin
像这样，你对 TMin 的返回值是什么？
Yeah the returns TMin in we'll talk a little bit basically
是的，我们的返回的是最小值，基本上会谈一点
When you try to negate this number that's here
当你试图否定这个在这里的数字
You'll end up with it back again
你会最终回来
So it's always a corner case and whenever we do program testing
所以，当我们进行程序测试时，它总是一个角落案例
We always throw that case in there to break things question
我们总是把那个案子扔在那里来解决问题
well that case you said oh yeah big number but how negative - one yes
那么你说，哦，是大数字，但如何消极 - 一个是的
No that's what they do that if you ever look at the in the C constance
不，那是他们这样做，如果你看过 C constance
They use this as a way of representing TMin
他们将此用作表示 TMin 的一种方式
And they do it for that reason because you see
因为你看到，所以他们这样做
It's exactly this problem and they put parentheses around it so there's no president's problem
这正是这个问题，他们把括号括在里面，所以没有总统的问题
But you see that number that in six for seven that's TMax
但是你看到那个数字是在六点七点那是 TMax
And so basically it's just saying that TMin is -TMax - 1
所以基本上只是说 TMin 是 -TMax-1
Question
请讲
[student speaking]
[学生发言]
yeah hmm yes
是的，嗯，是的
So comparison is just a special case of the more general one
所以比较只是更一般的特例
Which is addition subtraction all of those
这些都是加法减法
If either argument is unsigned then it interprets remaining one as being unsigned
如果任何一个参数都是无符号的，那么它将其余的解释为无符号
It turns out and we'll get into this more next time as far as bit patterns but
事实证明，我们将在下一次就位模式进入这一点，但是
But it turns out that at the bit level addition subtraction even multiplication
但事实证明，在位级减法甚至乘法
are the same whether it's an unsigned number two's complement number
无论它是一个无符号数的二进制补码是相同的
So what we'll talk about that more next time
所以下次我们会再谈这个问题
And the other thing to observe sort of property
另一件事是观察某种特性
is you saw that UMax is sort of like  2 * TMax + 1 right so
你是否看到 UMax 有点像 2*TMax+1
So before UMax was 15 in our five bit numbers
所以在 UMax 之前，我们的五位数字是 15
And and that's again not too hard to figure out
而且这也不难解决
Here's one way to think about it ,TMax is a zero followed by a bunch of ones
这里有一种思考方式，TMax 是一个零后面全是一
And if I want to double that number position
如果我想把这个数字乘以 2
I basically shift it left by one position
我基本上将它左移一个位置
And that would end up with a zero here
然后在结尾填 0
So this is TMax and this is twice TMax
所以这是 TMax，这是 TMax 的两倍
And now if I add a one to that
现在，如果我添加一个
That I'll just set this bit to one and get this
我只需将这一点设置为 1 即可
So there's various ways you can think about it but that's one way to do it
所以有多种方式可以考虑，但这是一种方法
It's one other thing that I wanted to mention too
这也是我想提及的另一件事
This can get you into a lot of trouble programming wise so let me just show you what I mean
这会让你在编程方面遇到很多麻烦，所以让我告诉你我的意思
So I mentioned I wanted to go backwards through an array
所以我提到我想通过数组倒退
So I write a loop of the form for (i=n-1;...
所以我写了一个形式为 i=n-1 的循环
i >= 0
i> = 0
i--
then I do something with array element a[i]
然后我用数组元素 a[i] 上做一些事情
I just call some function of
我只是调用一些函数
Whatever you want to do in that loop so that's a pretty standard pattern in a loop right
无论你想在循环中做什么，这是循环中的一个非常标准的模式
Except that you write this greater equal to1 0
除了你写这个大于等于 0
You can imagine various uses for that
你可以想象它的各种用途
So here's an interesting question what if I were declared as being unsigned
所以这里有一个有趣的问题，如果我被声明为未签名
Because it's array index after all what will happen with this loop
因为它是数组索引，毕竟这个循环会发生什么
What's that?
那是什么？
Yes! So the loop will go forever what would most likely happen is
是!所以循环将永远走到最可能发生的地步
I would go from being zero to being UMax
我会从零到成为 UMax
And that's a really big number and
这是一个非常大的数字
The way,you'd uh, most likely cause a memory fault because it's so far out of bounds
这种方式你可能会导致内存故障，因为它远远超出了界限
But the point is it wouldn't do what you want it wouldn't stop where you want it to
但重点是它不会做你想做的事，它不会停在你想要的地方
Because of the simple reason that i is of course
因为 i 是确定的
i is always going to be greater than or equal to zero because it's an unsigned number
i 总是会大于或等于零，因为它是一个无符号数
So that's one you'd say okay well you should have figured that one out
所以这是一个你会说好的，你应该想出一个
It can be fair it more subtle though
它可以是公平的，但它更微妙
If you have something like int i
如果你定义 int i
And then we say something like let me just change it here a little bit so this will be
然后我们说一些事情，比如让我在这里稍微改变一下，这样就可以了
Something like this where the I'm mixing metaphors here I have to confess
像这样的事情，我在这里混合比喻，我不得不承认
But if you use the standard the term size of which is the way you get
但是，如果你使用标准，那么你获得的方式就是其大小
How many bytes it takes to represent some given data type
给定数据类型需要多少字节
So this will actually be the number one
所以这实际上数字 1
So it's not the same loop as before but imagine I'm sort of mixing in my arithmetic and making use of some of these built-in forms
所以它不是像以前一样的循环，但想象一下，我在我的算术混合，并利用这些内置的形式
What would happen with this loop
这个循环会发生什么
Yes right yes
是的，是的
Exactly so sizeof returns an unsigned value
确实如此 sizeof 返回一个无符号值
It's not actually a function it's a built in but it's the result of sizeof is considered to be unsigned
它实际上不是它内置的函数，而是 sizeof 的结果被认为是未签名的
And so just like I was saying
就像我说的那样
If you have a signed value in it unsigned in any kind of arithmetic
如果你有一个有符号的值，它以任何类型的算术无符号
It'll turn treat the combination of the two is unsigned
它会转而处理两者的组合是无符号的
And so it will actually do an unsigned comparison here
所以它实际上会在这里做一个无符号的比较
Which is almost surely not what you wanted
这几乎肯定不是你想要的
And this will just you'll look at this program and you won't have any idea why it's crashing
这只是你看看这个程序，你不知道它为什么会崩溃
You'll be so confused and that's the kind of thing you have to know
你会很困惑，而这是你必须知道的事情
It's one of the quirks of C that probably a fake could start over again and redesign it
这是 C 的怪癖之一，可能是一个假的可能会重新开始并重新设计它
They'd come up with some different set of conventions than they did
他们想出了一些不同的约定
But unfortunately it's way too late for that so this is just one of those things you have to remember
但不幸的是，这太迟了，所以这只是你必须记住的事情之一
But yes the my point is through some subtleties to spent about in C
但是，是的，我的观点是通过一些微妙的东西来签名
About this business of signed versus unsigned arithmetic
关于有符号运算和无符号运算的业务
Okay so now let's look at a sort of final class of operations which is
好吧，现在我们来看一下最后一类的操作
Suppose I have a number that's so many bits say eight bits
假设我有一个数字，这么多位表示八位
And I want to now expand it to be a 16-bit number
我现在想把它扩展成一个 16 位数字
There's a fairly cute rule for doing this
这样做有一个相当可爱的规则
That's called sign extension I'm talking about two's complement numbers here
这就是所谓的符号扩展我在这里讨论的是补码数
Of how you go take a and make it bigger without changing its value
你如何去做并在不改变其价值的情况下做大
And the basic rule is you do it by copying  the sign bit to the left
基本规则是通过将符号位复制到左侧来完成
So let me give you the intuition behind it
所以让我给你一个背后的直觉
So let's go get some 4-bit values
所以让我们去获取一些 4 位值
Well it's pretty straightforward if the leading bit is a zero
如果前导位是零，那么它非常简单
I'm just going to do a left shift and then fill in so
我只是要做一个左移，然后填写
Wait what am I talking about
等一下我在说什么
I got ahead of myself I'm talking about something totally different
我领先于自己，我正在谈论完全不同的事情
No sorry the same number I'm not changing the number I keeping it  the same
没有抱歉，相同的号码，我不改变号码，我保持不变
So I just add a zero to the lead and this will be the number six still this is 4 + 2=6
所以我只是给主角加一个零，这将是六号仍然是 4+2=6
But now let's think about it as a where there's a leading sign bit
但是现在让我们想想最高位在哪里
So this is -8 + 4 + 2 = -2
所以这是 -8+4+2=-2
So now look at what happens if I copy that sign bit over one position
所以现在看看如果我将这个符号位复制到一个位置会发生什么
so this becomes a 11110
所以这变成了 11110
And what happens is this is a now has value plus 8 here
然后会发生什么，这是一个现在的值加 8 这里
But the sign bit has value -16
但符号位的值为 -16
And then this is still +2 and +4 and
然后这仍然是 +2 和 +4 和
So it will still equal -2
所以它仍然等于 -2
So here's what happened before my sign bit had a weight of -8
所以这是在我的符号位有 -8 的权重之前发生的事情
My new sign bit has a weight of -16
我的新符号位的重量为 -16
But I converted that old sign bit into a positive number which is +8
但我把那个旧的符号位转换成 +8 的正数
And those 2 cancelled out sit right the duck
而那两个取消了坐在鸭子
That you combine those two and you get a -8 which is exactly this
你把这两个结合起来，你就会得到一个 -8 这就是这个
So you see by sort of copying that sign bit over  giving it twice the weight turning it what was the sign bit into a positive number
所以你通过复制这种符号的方式看到它给了它两倍的权重，把它的符号位变成了正数
You don't change the net effect of the sum
你不改变总和的净效应
And that's exactly the idea of sign extension just keep going with that as far as you need to carry it over
这就是符号扩展的想法，只要您需要继续完成即可
And each time you're doing it you're effectively doing this business of coming up with a pair of bits
而且每次你​​做这件事时，你都会在做这个事情时想出一对双刃剑
that end up with the same value as this original bit
最终会得到与原始位相同的值
So that's the idea of sign extension and you'll see that a lot in bit patterns
所以这就是符号扩展的想法，你会看到很多位模式
Especially if you see a bit pattern with it starts with a bunch of Fs
特别是如果你看到一个位模式，它开始于一堆 Fs
What that tells you remember F is just four ones
那告诉你记得 F 只有四个
is a whole bunch of leading ones that tells you the number is negative
是一大堆领先的，告诉你这个数字是负数
Negative but not too far away from zero right
但是不会离零太远
And you'll see that over and over again you'll see bit patterns and you just sort of want it
而且你会一遍又一遍地看到你会看到一些模式，而你只是想要它
When you see leading Fs you say oh that's a negative number I know what's going on there
当你看到最高位都是F，你会说哦，这是一个负数，我知道那里发生了什么
And so here's some examples but like you can see the main idea is you carry that leading bit
所以这里有一些例子，但是你可以看到主要想法是你携带那个领先的位
from the 16-bit case over and make as many copies you need to expand the word size
从 16 位的情况下，并作出尽可能多的副本，你需要扩大字的大小
And I should mention with the unsigned case obviously you just want to fill in with zeros
我应该提及无符号数的情况，显然你只是想填充零
To talk about truncation and send missing slides in this but um
谈论截断并发送失踪的幻灯片，但这个
A final case to look at is what happens if I make something shorter
最后一个要看的例子是如果我缩短一些东西会发生什么
So if I had my unsigned number from before
所以如果我之前有我的无符号数
If this were an unsigned number this would be
如果这是一个无符号数字，这将是
1 2 8 16 14 17 right
1、2、8、16、14、17
What if I decided oh I can't afford 4 bit I don't have enough money for 5 bits I'm only going to give you 4
如果我决定哦，我买不起 4 位，我没有 5 位数的钱，我只给你 4
Well you basically just drop the most significant bit
那么你基本上只是丢弃掉最高位
And you get 8 + 2 + 1 which is 11
你得到 8+2+1 这是 11
Which is 9 and the relation there is that this is a it's like modular arithmetic
这是 9 和它的关系，这是一个它就像模运算
Right mod 16 you're taking...no
正确的 mod 16 你正在采取...不
Thank you
谢谢
It's the risk of improvising so 27 and 11
所以这是即兴创作的风险，那么实验一下 27 和 11
Yeah it makes sense,difference is 16  that I knew that
是的，这是有道理的，我知道的不同是 16
Okay excuse me for my stumbling
好，请原谅我设置的障碍
But the point being that when you drop this thing effectively you're just taking the mod some power of 2 of it like
但重要的是，当你有效地放弃这件事情时，你只是将 mod 2的幂
I mentioned the case where you're taking module 8
我提到了你采用模块 8 的情况
If you just keep only the lowest order 3 bits you're having a module 8
如果你只保留最低 3 位，你有一个模 8
Now one really this is a sort of logical in the unsigned world
现在，这是在无符号数中的逻辑
Your modular arithmetic is something that was understood by the ancient Greeks
模运算是古希腊人所理解的
So not too far away from human experience
所以离人类经验不太远
But it gets a little bit funky if you're dealing with two's complement numbers
但是如果你处理二进制补码，它会变得有点时髦
Because this is now 10 11 -5 right
因为这现在是 10、11、 -5
But this number if I just drop this bit and
但是这个数字，如果我丢弃这一位
And call it a 4-bit number this now becomes -8,2,1
并将其称为 4 位数字，现在变成 -8,2,1
It's -5
它是 -5
You say how'd that happen well actually if you look at it this is just what you'd get by sign extension right
你说过，如果你看到它，那么它实际上发生得很好，这正是你通过签名扩展获得的权利
So this wasn't a very interesting example
所以这不是一个很有趣的例子
But if we changed it to this
但是，如果我们改变这一点
Then this would be -13
那么这将是 -13
And this would be +3
这将是 +3
And it's a little harder to think about in terms of modular arithmetic
就模运算而言，思考有点困难
The way you basically have to think about it is well
你基本上必须考虑的方式很好
You know this is -13 but it's really kind of like 27 and  27 mod 16 is sort of like or,no this isn't 20
你知道这是 -13，但它有点像 27 和 27 模 16 有点像，或者这不是 20
We changed our number right so this is really kind of like 19.And 19 mod 16 is 3.And this is 3
我们改变了我们的号码，所以这真的有点像 19。19 模 16 是 3，这是 3
So you can sort of do it by coming back around to it
所以你可以通过回头来做到这一点
But it's not sum of arithmetic property that would jump out at you as being something logical
但它不是算术属性的总和，会跳出你的逻辑
But that happens all the time that and it's very common
但是这种情况一直发生，这很常见
For numbers to get truncated for one reason or another
数字因某种原因被截断
And you can see that you can have a negative number become a positive number
你可以看到你可以有一个负数成为一个正数
You can have a positive number become a negative number
你可以让一个正数成为负数
And all kinds of goofy stuff can happen
而各种愚蠢的东西都可能发生
And we'll see plenty examples of that when we look at arithmetic
当我们看看算术时，我们会看到很多例子
So that's,that is what I want to cover today
所以这就是我今天想要介绍的内容
And we'll cover the other arithmetic operations on Tuesday
我们将在周二介绍其他算术运算
So thank you very much
非常感谢你们